# **Andi Crotwell**

# Software Engineer

• Anaheim, CA awcrotwell@gmail.com awcrotwell.com awcrotwell in awcrotwell

#### **PROFILE**

I am a full stack and distributed systems engineer with a passion for tinkering. I have expertise in designing, implementing, and scaling distributed architectures. I also have multiple years of experience building consumer facing software with a proficiency in Ruby, Go, NodeJS, JavaScript, TypeScript and AWS.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages Ruby, Go, Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Crystal **Frameworks**Ruby on Rails, ExpressJS,
Sinatra, React, NextJS

**Technologies**Git, NodeJS, Redux, Docker,
PostgreSQL, MongoDB,
Redis, RESTful API's,
GraphQL

**Cloud** AWS, Heroku

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer2021 – presentDendroAsheville, NC

- Co-created and deployed an open source, real-time, distributed log centralization pipeline utilizing languages & technologies such as Go, TypeScript, React & NextJS
- Researched and implemented a multi-service logging pipeline on AWS using services such as Kinesis Firehose, S3, Lambda, Timestream and SNS
- Created a Go lang application to ingest and transform logs into time-series data in real-time
- Designed the alerting and monitoring system to notify operators of system failures in near real-time
- Managed the migration from JavaScript to TypeScript
- Created a React/NextJS application in Typescript to view, query & monitor health metrics
- Co-authored the case study for Dendro https://getdendro.com

Software Engineer 2020 – 2021 BridgeAPI Asheville, NC

- Co-created BridgeAPI, an open-source serverless integration platform to connect apps through event-driven workflows
- Built the backend workflow to receive, save, filter, and forward HTTP requests
- Developed a background job processor to handle multiple events concurrently using Sidekiq and Redis
- Implemented user authentication and authorization using JSON web tokens (JWT)
- Built the React frontend using NextJS
- Deployed the app to AWS (EB, EC2, S3, Lambda, Aurora, CloudFront)
- Created testing suites of the backend using RSpec and of the frontend using Cypress
- Co-authored the case study for BridgeAPI: https://bridgeapi-dev.github.io/ &

### Freelance Software Engineer

2018 - 2020

- RequestBin: A Ruby on Rails application to capture and monitor webhooks and API requests
- Jello Task Manager: A kanban board application built with React, Redux, ExpressJS and MongoDB
- Serverless.cr: An AWS Lambda custom runtime to run Crystal applications
- Motion.cr: A framework for building reactive, real-time frontend UI components
- Mochi: An authentication library for the Amber framework

## **EDUCATION**

Launch School 05/2019 - 06/2021

Multi-year full-stack software engineering curriculum emphasizing mastery of core skills and programming fundamentals launchschool.com/employers &